A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 3255-6261 FA739B
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Agricultural research and the Ford Foundation (Reports 005000), 1966 (Box 222)
  Agriculture -- Research -- Developing countries; Agricultural development projects -- Developing countries; Soil conservation -- Developing countries; Tropical crops -- Research -- Developing countries; Dry farming -- Developing countries; International Rice Research Institute; International Institute of Tropical Agriculture
- Some recent uses of social development consultants on difficult assignments (Reports 005001), 1967 (Box 222)
  Memorandum to McGeorge Bundy dated August 17, 1967.
  Social planning -- United States; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation; Community development -- Ohio; Technical assistance -- Mississippi; Minorities -- Employment -- California; Minority business enterprises -- United States; Congress of Racial Equality; Mississippi Research and Development Center; Interracial Council for Business Opportunity
- Outline of organizational steps and procedures for creation and operation of minority contractor bonding program (Reports 005002), 1968 (Box 222)
  Minority contractor bonding program
  African American businesspeople; Minority business enterprises -- United States; Contractors -- Insurance requirements -- United States; Construction industry -- Insurance -- United States -- Specifications; Construction -- Equipment and supplies
- On the future of technical assistance (Reports 005003), 1969 (Box 222)
  Paper ... prepared ... as a contribution to a volume of essays honoring Edward S. Mason on his retirement from Harvard University. -- T.p.
  Technical assistance -- Developing countries; Economic assistance -- Developing countries; Social development -- Developing countries; Industrial organization -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Women's roles in development: Pakistan consultancy report (Reports 005004), 1976 (Box 222)
  Memo dated September 27, 1977 describing consultancy in role of Pakistani women in that country's development (August 13-August 27, 1976).
  [Pakistan consultancy report];[Women's roles in development]
  Women in development -- Pakistan; Women -- Pakistan -- Social conditions; Women -- Education -- Pakistan; Social planning -- Pakistan; Social change -- Pakistan; Sex role -- Pakistan; Ford Foundation. Field Office Islamabad; Ford Foundation Pakistan
- Consultancy on Brazilian women's roles in development, June 20-July 9 (Reports 005005), 1976 (Box 222)
  Memo to Eduardo Venezian dated August 2, 1976.
  14 p. + appendices
  Brazilian women's roles in development
  Women in development -- Brazil; Women -- Research -- Brazil; Women -- Brazil -- Social conditions; Women -- Education -- Brazil; Women in agriculture -- Brazil; Women -- Brazil -- Social conditions; Women -- Health and hygiene -- Brazil; Social planning -- Brazil
- The "New Home Economics": insights on development problems (Reports 005006), 1976 (Box 222)
  Memo dated December 3, 1976.
  10 p. + appendices
  Women in development -- Developing countries; Women -- Developing countries -- Economic conditions; Women -- Developing countries -- Social conditions; Social role -- Developing countries; Sex role -- Developing countries
- Women and National Development Policy: issues to consider in the Sudan (Reports 005007), 1979 (Box 222)
  Paper prepared for a symposium on "The Changing Roles of Sudanese Women", February 23-March 1, 1979, El Ahfad University College for Women, Khartoum.
  Women in development -- Sudan; Women -- Sudan -- Economic conditions; Women -- Sudan -- Social conditions; Women -- Employment -- Sudan; Women's rights -- Sudan
- Poor women: a new-feminist view (Reports 005008), 1975 (Box 222)
  Women in development -- Developing countries; Women -- Developing countries -- Economic conditions; Women -- Employment -- Developing countries; Women -- Developing countries -- Social conditions; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc.
- The status and roles of Ghanaian and Kenyan women: Implications for fertility behavior (Reports 005009), 1974 (Box 222)
  Paper presented at annual meeting of the American Psychological Association, September 1, 1974, on"Women's Status and Fertility around the World. -- T.p.
  41 p. + attachment
  Women in development -- Ghana; Women in development -- Kenya; Women -- Education -- Ghana; Women -- Education -- Kenya; Women -- Employment -- Ghana; Women -- Employment -- Kenya; Sex role -- Ghana; Sex role -- Kenya; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc.
- Some aspects of the roles of women in population and development (Reports 005010), 1974 (Box 222)
  Background paper for the International Women's Forum. -- T.p.
  Women in population and development
  Women in development -- Developing countries; Women -- Education -- Developing countries; Women -- Employment -- Developing countries; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Birth control -- Developing countries; Migration, Internal
- Fertility control in the Third World: where do we go from here? (Reports 005011), 1973 (Box 222)
  Birth control -- Research -- Developing countries; Birth control -- Political aspects -- Developing countries; Fertility, Human -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Analysis of sex differentials in 1976-77 Egyptian farm management survey data: review of my consultancy (Reports 005012), 1979 (Box 222)
  Memo to James Fitch dated March 20, 1979.
  07690804;PA775-149.
  Development of women's program.
  Women -- Research -- Egypt; Women -- Employment -- Egypt -- Surveys; Agriculture -- Religious aspects -- Islam; Women farmers -- Egypt; Sex role -- Egypt; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- Symposium on the changing status of Sudanese women, February 23-March 1, El Ahfad University College (Reports 005013), 1979 (Box 222)
  Memo to Guillaume de Spoelberch and John Bruce.
  Women's rights -- Sudan
- Economic growth, household production strategies and sex differentiation of wage rates and productive work opportunities: the case of Thailand (Reports 005014), 1978 (Box 222)
  Memo to Peter Geithner dated October 27, 1978.
  12 p. + attachments
  Women -- Employment -- Thailand; Women -- Thailand -- Economic conditions; Wage differentials -- Thailand; Sex discrimination -- Thailand; Labor supply -- Research -- Thailand; Migration, Internal -- Thailand
- Consultancy on women's roles in Mexican development, June 1-10 (Reports 005015), 1977 (Box 222)
  Memo to Robert Drysdale dated July 11, 1977.
  Women's roles in Mexican development
  Women in development -- Mexico; Women -- Research -- Mexico; Women -- Mexico -- Social conditions; Ford Foundation Brazil
- Consultancy on the roles and status of women in Jamaica (Reports 005016), 1977 (Box 222)
  Memo to Barry Schuman, Robert Wickham and ID committee dated February 25, 1977.
  Status of women in Jamaica
  Women in development -- Jamaica; Women -- Research -- Jamaica; Women -- Education -- Jamaica; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Women -- Jamaica -- Social conditions; Sex role -- Jamaica; Women -- Jamaica -- Societies and clubs; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- The refugee experience: an overview of refugee research (Reports 005017), 1980 (Box 222)
  Paper presented as a conference on The Refugee Experience sponsored by the Royal Anthropological Institute and the Minority Rights Group, London, February 22-24, 1980. -- T.p.
  PA76-811.
  26 p. + attachments
  Refugees -- Research -- Developing countries; Refugees -- Developing countries -- Social conditions
- Activities of the Ford Foundation in Burma: informational meeting (Reports 005018), 1953 (Box 222)
  Transcript of informational meeting held on December 3, 1953.
  34 leaves
  Public administration -- Burma; Chinese -- Burma; Communism -- Burma; Education, Higher -- Burma; Literacy -- Burma; Land tenure -- Burma; Ford Foundation
- Meeting on the Board of Trustees (Reports 005019), 1955 (Box 222)
  Special discussion paper addressed to Mr. H. Rowan Gaither, Jr. on the Fund for the Republic.
  Fund for the Republic
  Freedom of expression -- United States; Civil liberties -- United States; Human rights -- United States; Fund for the Republic; Ford Foundation
- Toward an open foreign policy (Reports 005020), 1973 (Box 222)
  A background paper from Mr. Bundy to the Commission for the Organization of Government for the Conduct of Foreign Policy. -- T.p.
  Presidents -- United States; Diplomacy; Ford Foundation. Office of the President
- Resources for the future: Otlook - 1971 (Reports 005021) (Box 222)
  Natural resources -- United States -- Management; Conservation of natural resources -- United States; Resources for the Future
- Not such innocents abroad: the Ford Foundation in India (Reports 005022), 1966 (Box 222)
  Discussion of the population and food supply problems in India and the Ford Foundation's five year plan to alleviate the problems.
  Asia and the Pacific;India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  Ford Foundation in India
  Food supply -- India
- Government, the arts, and ghetto youth (Reports 005023), 1970 (Box 222)
  Prepared for publication in a spring, 1970, issue of Public Administration Review. -- T.p.
  31 p. + attachment
  Arts -- United States -- Finance; Federal aid to the arts -- United States; Arts and society -- United States; Arts and the poor -- United States -- Case studies; Arts and youth -- United States -- Case studies; Urban youth -- United States; Minorities in art; Ford Foundation. Humanities and the Arts
- Participation, decentralization, community control and quality education (Reports 005024), 1969 (Box 222, Reel R-9302)
  Education, Urban -- United States; Community and school -- United States; Public schools -- United States; School integration -- United States; African American students; Educational change -- United States; Education -- Political aspects -- United States
- Community control and quality education in urban school systems (Reports 005025), 1968 (Box 223)
  49 p.: ill., chart
- Kenya Tour report (Reports 005026), 1967 (Box 223)
  Consultant report on activities in Kenya (August 1965 to June 1967).
  PA64-5.
  7 leaves
  Public administration -- Kenya; Educational assistance -- Kenya; Technical assistance -- Kenya; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Fellowship programs in business administration and economics (Reports 005028), 1958 (Box 223)
  7 p. + attachment
  Women -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Women -- Education, Higher -- United States; Scholarships -- United States
- Social research and population policy summary and recommendations (Reports 005029), 1973 (Box 223)
  Population -- Research -- Developing countries; Population assistance -- Developing countries; Social sciences -- Research -- Developing countries; Birth control -- Research -- Developing countries; Fertility, Human -- Research -- Developing countries
- Private foundation and conservation (Reports 005030), 1969 (Box 223)
  Ecology -- United States; Ecology -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; Natural resources -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- United States
- Pakistan's future and the Ford Foundation: some tentative observations (Reports 005031), 1969 (Box 223)
  Economic assistance -- Pakistan; Economic assistance -- Bangladesh; Educational assistance -- Pakistan; Educational assistance -- Bangladesh
- On sports (Reports 005032), 1977 (Box 223)
  Education and Research/Public Broadcasting
  College sports -- United States; Sports journalism -- United States; Mass media and sports -- United States; Athletes in mass media; National Collegiate Athletic Association
- The uses and abuses of performance measurement (Reports 005033), 1973 (Box 223)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Nonprofit organizations -- United States -- Finance; Portfolio management -- United States; Investments -- United States; Securities -- United States; Ford Foundation
- Patterns of conflict in African public administration (Reports 005034), 1968 (Box 223)
  African public administration
  Public administration -- Africa, Sub-Saharan; Civil service -- Africa, Sub-Saharan
- Foundation reporting (Reports 005035), 1969 (Box 223)
  Nonprofit organizations -- United States -- Marketing; Charity organization -- United States; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Evaluation
- Training the trainers: 3rd Conference of Directors of Institutes of Public Administration in the Commonwealth (Reports 005036), 1970 (Box 223)
  Written for the Third Conference of Directors of Institutes of Public Administration in the Commonwealth. Training staff members to teach public administration staff.
  5 p. + appendices.
  Training -- Saudi Arabia; Public administration -- Study and teaching -- Saudi Arabia
- How do archival concerns measure among developmental priorities? (Reports 005037), 1971 (Box 223)
  DA
  14 p. + attachment
  Archival materials -- Conservation and restoration -- Developing countries; Records -- Developing countries -- Management; Cultural property -- Developing countries; Technical assistance -- Developing countries; Endowments -- Developing countries
- The Ford Foundation (Reports 005038), 1971 (Box 223)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States; Endowments -- United States; Economic assistance, Domestic -- United States; Libraries -- United States -- Finance; Libraries -- Developing countries -- Finance; Library science -- Study and teaching; Ford Foundation
- International philanthropy: Using a case study for dimension (Reports 005039), 1971 (Box 223)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States; Endowments -- Developing countries; Educational assisstance -- Developing countries; Libraries -- Developing countries -- Finance
- Social problems of the future (Reports 005040), 1968 (Box 223)
  47 p.: tables, chart
  Social problems -- United States; Quality of life -- United States
- Family planning service delivery: options and trends (Reports 005041), 1976 (Box 223)
  27, 7 p.
  Birth control -- Brazil; Contraception -- Brazil; Contraceptives -- Brazil; Ford Foundation. Field Office Rio de Janeiro
- Contraceptive development for developing countries: unmet needs (Reports 005042), 1975 (Box 223)
  16 p.: ill -- 28 cm.
  [Ford Foundation Publications]
  Contraceptives -- Research; Contraception -- Research; Population research; Population policy; Fertility, Human -- Research; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- The state of siege (Reports 005043), 1968 (Box 223)
  War and society; World history -- 20th century
- The size of the Foundation (Reports 005044), 1972 (Box 223)
  Memo to McGeorge Bundy dated November 20, 1972.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Administration; Nonprofit organizations -- United States -- Administration; Endowments -- United States -- Management; Ford Foundation Management; Ford Foundation -- Planning
- Organized labor and organized philanthropy (Reports 005045), 1975 (Box 223)
  Labor -- United States; Labor unions -- United States; Working class -- United States; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States; Endowments -- United States
- Knowing, acting, and making: a note on the college curriculum (Reports 005046), 1970 (Box 223)
  6 p.: ill., chart
  Education, Higher -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States -- Curricula; Arts -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; Science -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States
- Program for Area III on Economic Development and Administration (Reports 005047), 1954 (Box 223, Reel R-9302)
  Preface -- I. Recommendations -- II. Approach to program III -- III. Proposed activities -- IV. Procedures -- Concluding comment.
  Economics -- Research -- Developing countries; Economic development -- Developing Countries; Economic stabilization -- Developing countries; Economics -- Study and teaching (Graduate); International economic relations; Endowments -- United States; Ford Foundation. Economic Development and Administration; Ford Foundation
- Research and training needs in water management for food production (Reports 005048), 1970 (Box 223)
  10 p.: charts
  Irrigation -- Developing countries -- Congresses; Water -- Management -- Congresses; Soil management -- Developing countries -- Congresses; Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Developing countries
- Natural sciences, mathematics and engineering education (Reports 005049), 1955 (Box 223)
  Science -- Study and teaching -- United States; Mathematics -- Study and teaching -- United States; Engineering -- Study and teaching -- United States; Ford Foundation
- A cultural affairs program (Reports 005050), 1955 (Box 223)
  Memo to the Trustees.
  Arts -- United States -- Finance; Performing arts -- United States -- Finance; Museums -- United States -- Finance; Artists -- United States -- Finance
- Progress report: survey of problems of the handicapped (Reports 005051), 1956 (Box 223)
  People with disabilities -- Research -- United States; People with disabilities -- Rehabilitation -- United States; People with disabilities -- Education--United States; People with mental disabilities -- Education -- United States; Sociology of disability; Ford Foundation
- The Ford Foundation Science and Engineering Program: outline for discussion at meeting of trustees, March 22-23 (Reports 005052), 1957 (Box 223)
  Science -- Study and teaching -- United States; Engineering -- Study and teaching -- United States; Radiation -- Research; Nuclear energy -- Research; Ford Foundation. Science and Engineering.
- Break-through in teacher education (Reports 005053), 1957 (Box 223)
  Teachers -- Training of -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States; Ford Foundation
- Suggestions for 10-point pilot program to increase food production -- summary (Reports 005054), 1959 (Box 223)
  10-Point Pilot Program to Increase Food Production: summary
  Agricultural productivity -- Developing countries; Agricultural assistance -- Developing countries; Agricultural development projects -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program
- Public affairs: proposed activities concerned with the problems of migration (Reports 005055), 1959 (Box 223)
  Migration, Internal -- United States; Migration, Internal -- Economic aspects -- United States; Labor supply -- United States
- Memorandum on preliminary phase of follow-up project (Reports 005056), 1960 (Box 223)
  Reviewing 19 Public Affairs grants in Social Science and Law, and "government improvement" to Harvard, Yale, Columbia, University of California and University of Chicago, among others, dating from 1955-1959, the author asks, "How effective have we been? W
  41 p.;28 cm.
  Law -- Study and teaching -- Program evaluation; Political science -- Study and teaching -- Program evaluation; Ford Foundation. Public Affairs
- South and Southeast Asia: review of 1962 and projection (Reports 005057) (Box 223)
  Memorandum to F.F. Hill dated December 11, 1962.
  9 p. + attachments:
  Economics -- Research -- Southeast Asia; Social sciences -- Research -- Southeast Asia; Education -- Southeast Asia; Vocational education -- Southeast Asia; Public administration -- Southeast Asia; Rural development -- Southeast Asia; Endowments -- Southeast Asia; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program
- Activities to foster cooperative links within the Atlantic area (Reports 005058), 1963 (Box 223)
  International cooperation; Ford Foundation. International Affairs
- Ford Foundation strategy for strengthening Latin American studies in the United States (Reports 005059), 1963 (Box 224)
  Latin America -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; Ford Foundation. International Training and Research.
- International Affairs discussion paper: review of IA-supported conferences and meetings (Reports 005060), 1964 (Box 224)
  "Review and appraisal of IA-supported conferences and meetings over the past ten years, together with conclusions and recommendations for the future" -- T.p.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Congresses; Educational assistance -- Developing countries -- Congresses; International relations; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation
- Projections of manpower demand and supply 1971-1986 and policy and program suggestions for Bahrain (Reports 005061), 1974 (Box 224)
  268 p.: tables -- 32 cm.
  Manpower planning -- Bahrain; Manpower policy -- Bahrain; Manpower -- Bahrain; Labor supply -- Bahrain; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- EIA program for international affairs institutes and related activities (Reports 005062), 1970 (Box 224)
  International relations -- Study and teaching; International cooperation -- Study and teaching; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Europe; Endowments -- United States; Endowments -- Europe
- A listing of Ford Foundation-supported institutions in the U.S. and Europe offering fellowships for training and research in demography and family planning (Reports 005063), 1969 (Box 224)
  Ford Foundation-supported institutions in the U.S. ...
  Birth control -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; Social sciences -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; Public health -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States; Scholarships -- United States; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Assessment of population situation in Tanzania: based on visit of 30-31 July, 1969, and auxiliary materials (Reports 005064) (Box 224)
  Letter to John Robin and David Anderson dated September 18, 1969.
  Population situation in Tanzania ...
  Birth control -- Tanzania; Birth control -- Study and teaching -- Tanzania; Birth control clinics -- Tanzania; Population assistance -- Tanzania; Chama cha Uzazi na Malezi Bora Tanzania
- The Foundation, the social sciences, and Latin America (Reports 005065), 1976 (Box 224)
  L75-245.
  PAPER Conference (1976 Apr. 26-28: Villa de Leyva, Colombia)
  Social sciences -- Latin America
- Visit to the Education Program for French Iron Ore Miners (Reports 005066), 1970 (Box 224)
  Iron miners -- Education -- France; Iron mines and mining -- France; Mechanics -- Study and teaching -- France
- Report on the CELADE workshop on evaluation of family planning programs, 5-10, January 1970, in Santiago (Reports 005067) (Box 224)
  File memo dated January 30, 1970.
  CELADE workshop on evaluation of family planning program ...
  Population research -- Latin America -- Congresses; Birth control -- Latin America -- Congresses; Fertility, Human -- Latin America -- Congresses; CELADE (Organization)
- Perspectives and industry position papers for 1977 (Reports 005068), 1976 (Box 224)
  223 p. + attachments: tables
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Nonprofit organizations -- United States -- Finance; Portfolio management -- United States -- Finance; Investments -- United States; Securities -- United States; Economics -- Political aspect; Ford Foundation. Investment Research; Ford Foundation
- International portfolio diversification (Reports 005069), 1978 (Box 224)
  53 p. + appendices
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Nonprofit organizations -- United States -- Finance; Investments, Foreign -- United States; Portfolio management -- United States; Securities -- United States; Stocks -- United States; Ford Foundation
- Financial management costs (Reports 005070), 1979 (Box 224)
  15 p. + appendix: tables
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Nonprofit organizations -- United States -- Finance; Portfolio management -- United States; Securities -- United States; Ford Foundation